Guide to the Amado M. Padilla Papers M0497
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Spanish Speaking Mental Health Research Center (SSMHRC)
  - Other mental health papers
    - J. Casas and S. Keefe, eds., Family and Mental Health in the Mexican American Community, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - T. Escobedo, ed., Education and Chicanos: Issues and Research, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - K. Lindholm, G. Marin, R. Lopez, Proposal Writing Stategies, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - M. Gilbert and R. Cervantes, eds., Mexican Americans and Alcohol, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - The Special Populations Sub-Task panel on Mental Health of Hispanic Americans, Report to the President's Commission on Mental Health, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Proceedings of the National Conference of Hispanic Psychologists, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - A. Padilla and R. Ruiz, Latino Mental Health. A Review of Literature, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - A. Padilla and P. Arand, Latino Mental Health. Bibliography and Abstracts, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - SSMRC Research Bulletins, 1976-1985
    - 1976 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 1977 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 1978 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 1979 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - 1980 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 1983 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 1984 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - 1985 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Budget Files
    - 1973 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 1974 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - 1975 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 1976 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - 1977 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - SF-21, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - SF-22, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - SF-21, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - SF-22, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - PX-18, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - PX-19, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - PX-18, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - PX-18, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Progress and Evaluation Reports, Grant Proposals, etc., 1973-1988
    - SSMHRC Progress Report 01, 1 July 1973-31 May 1975, 1973-1975 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Grant Budget Material 02, 1974-1976 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Application for Continuation Grant 02--Original Grant (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report 02, 1 July 1975-30 November 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Mail Survey for SSMHRC Evaluation, 1976 (Box 54, Folders 1-2)
    - Grant Budget Material 03, 1976-1977 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report 03, 1 December 1976-30 November 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report 03, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Evaluation, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Final Report of the Urban Institute for Human Services, Inc., to NIMH, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - SSMHRC Renewal Proposal 04, 1978-1983 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - SSMHRC Renewal Proposal 04, Proposal only, 1978-1983 (Box 51, Folders 9-10)
    - SSMHRC Renewal, 1978-1983 (Box 51, Folders 11-13)
    - Grant Budget Material 05, 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Grant Budget Material 04-05, 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report 05, 1 December 1978-30 November 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Grant budget Material 06, 1979-1980 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 06 1 December 1978-30 November 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Grant Budget Material 07, 1980-1981 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 07 1 December 1980-30 November 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - NIMH Site Visit, 1981 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Grant Budget Material 08, 1981-1982 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 08 1 December 1981-30 November 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Dr. Alvin So's Report, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Grant Budget Material 09, 1982-1983 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Renewal Proposal 09, 1983-1989 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Addendum to SSMHRC Renewal Proposal, 09, 1983-1989 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Grant Budget Material, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - SSMHRC Site Visit, 1983-01-21 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 1 January 1984-31 December 1984 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Grant Budget Material, 1984 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Grant Increase for SSMHRC, 1984 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - NIMH Site Visit, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 1 January 1985-31 December 1985 (Box 53, Folders 4-5)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 1985 (Box 53, Folders 6-7)
    - SSMHRC Progress Report, 1986 (Box 53, Folders 8-9)
    - Grant Budget Material, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Budget Material, Evaluation of SSMHRC and Development Centers, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - NIMH Site Visit/Evaluation, 1986-04 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Evaluation Report, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - SSMHRC Self-Statement, 3 Funding Cycles, 1973-1988 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - NIMH Grant to SSMHRC, 3/1/79-12/31/88, 1979-1988 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Applications, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 4-5)
    - Applicant List, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Announcements, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - NIMH/NIAA Budget, etc., 1983-1987
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, internal, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Scholar in Hispanic Alcohol Studies Budget, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - NIAA Grant Budget Material, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence on Academic Papers, Incoming, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, internal, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence on Academic Papers, Incoming, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, internal, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Grant Materials, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - NIMH Workshop, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - NIMH Paper, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Staff, 1979-1988
    - Hiring, Assistant Research Anthropologist (Temporary), 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Recruitment, Hiring, Merit Increase, Assistant Clinical Research Psychologist, 1983-1984 (Box 45, Folders 2-3)
    - Recruitment, Hiring, Merit Increase, Scholar on Hispanic Alcohol Studies, 1984-1987 (Box 45, Folders 4-5)
    - Hiring, Assistant Research Psychologist, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Hiring and Merit Increases, Assistant Research Psychologist, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Recruitment, Secretary II and Word Processing Specialist, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1983-1986 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Staff Monthly Reports, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Staff Monthly Reports, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Staff Monthly Reports, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Staff Letters of Resignation, 1982-1988 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Consultant Agreements, 1979-1984 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1988
    - General Incoming, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Space Allocation, 1976-1977 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Grant MH24854, 1976-1977 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Memos, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Incoming, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Internal, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Incoming, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Outgoing, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Internal, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Incoming, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Outgoing, 1984 (Box 47, Folders 17-20, Box 48, Folders 1-8)
    - Internal, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Incoming, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Outgoing, 1985 (Box 49, Folders 1-6, Box 48, Folders 12-17)
    - Internal, 1985 (Box 49, Folders 7-8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Incoming, 1986 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Outgoing, 1986 (Box 50, Folders 1-4, Box 49, Folders 11-18)
    - Internal, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Incoming, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Outgoing, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Internal, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Outgoing, 1988 (Box 50, Folders 7-16)
    - Internal, 1988 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous papers, correspondence, notes, etc.
    - Alcoholism in the Spanish-Speaking Community, Background Material, 1973-1975 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Hildago Study, Cross Cultural Alcoholism and Acculturation (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Grant Proposal Drafts, 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folders 4-6)
    - Survey on Involvement in Alcoholism at UCLA Campus, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Raymond Buriel, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Martha Bernal, Post-doctoral Proposal (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Manuel Barrera (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Eduardo Cascallar, UCLA-Mexico Earthquake Study (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Felipe Castro, Cocaine Use and Health Habits (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Richard Cervantes, Publications (Box 31, Folders 6-7)
    - Felipe Castro and Richard Cervantes, UCLA Senate, Psychological Stress Among Mexican Americans (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - M. Jean Gilbert, UCMexus, U.S.-Mexico Conference (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - M. Jean Gilbert, NIAAA, U.S.-Mexico Conference (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - R. Gonsalves, Mexican American Developmental Expectancies (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Susan Keefe, The Mexican American Extended Family (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Ellen Liebman and Amado Padilla, Bilingual Language Acquisition (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Kathryn Lindholm, Incest in Hispanic Families (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Kathryn Lindholm, Impact of Incest on Females, Proposal (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Spero Manson, Health and Behavior: Research Agenda for Amerinds, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Gerardo Marin, Development of Posters for Latinos, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Gerardo Marin, Review on Effects of Family Size, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Gerardo Marin, Sex Typed Attributions: A Cross-Cultural Analysis (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Gerardo Marin and Barbara Marin, Discontinuance of Oral Contaceptives in Hispanic Women--Ortho, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Gerardo Marin and Barbara Marin, Young Males Program, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Gerardo Marin, Barbara Marin, and Amado Padilla, Psychosocial Dimensions of Family Planning Among Chicanos, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Gerardo Marin and Harry Triardis, Hispanic Subjective Culture, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Manuel Mirarda and Amado Padilla, Barriers to Mental Health Services, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Richard Morris, Stress and Adaptation Among Recent Mexican Immigrants, Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 32, Folder 13, Box 33, Folders 1-2)
    - Frank Newton, Adjustment to Aging Among Mexican Americans, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Frank Newton, Hispanic Mental Health Bibliographic Data Base, 1979-1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Frank Newton, Sex Differences in the Health of Chicano Elderly, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - National Network of Hispanic Women, 1984-1985 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (NPI) Subcontract, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Esteban Olmedo, Substance Abuse in Mexican American Youth, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Esteban Olmedo, Relevance of Acculturation to Hispanic Mental Health, 1978 (Box 34, Folders 1-2)
    - Esteban Olmedo, Hispanic Mental Health Bibliographic System, 1977-1978 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Amado M. Padilla, G. Marin, B. Marin, Barriers to Health Care, 1979-1980 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Amado M. Padilla and Kathryn Lindholm, Communicative Socialization Patterns and Strategies in 1st and 3rd Generations, NIE, 1979 (Box 35, Folders 1-3)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Factors Influencing Academic Success or Nonsuccess of Mexican American Students, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Amado M. Padilla and Kathryn Lindholm, How Parents Teach, 1981 (Box 35, Folders 5-6)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Linguistic Interaction and Translation in the Speech of Bilingual Children, UCLA Research Grant, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Hispanic American Doctoral Recipients Proposal, USDOL, 1977 (Box 35, Folders 8-9)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Hispanic Infant Development Project, 1978 (Box 35, Folders 10-11)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Hispanic Mental Health Research Bibliography Proposal, 1981 (Box 36, Folders 1-2)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Language Acquisition in the Bilingual Child, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Amado M. Padilla, Mental Health Service Utilization by Mexican Americans, 1973-1978 (Box 36, Folders 4-5)
    - Amado M. Padilla, UCLA Senate Awards and Other Proposals, 1982-1984 (Box 36, Folders 6)
    - Padilla, Anenhansel, Proposal for Center for Research and Demonstration of Health Promotion and Disease Prevention, 1986 (Box 36, Folders 7)
    - Robert Perez, Psychosocial Factors Influencing Pregnancy Outcome in a Sample of Hispanic Women, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Lloyd Rogler, Alcoholism Research Project Proposal, 1982-1984 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Rene Ruiz, Research on Training in Hispanic Mental Health, 1978 (Box 38, Folders 7-8)
    - Gloria Romero, Women Without Work: Stress and Coping Among Latinos and Blacks, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Nelly Salgado de Snyder, UCLA Program, Mexico Conference, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - John Townsend, Ethnicity and Parental Tasks, 1979-1981 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - John Townsend, Divorce and Custody: Anglos and Mexican Americans, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Articles, Miscellaneous, 1984-1987 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Student Papers, 1986-1987 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Special Report, NIMH, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Hispanic Mental Health Research Center (HMHRC), 1987-1988
    - NIMH Minority Mental Health Research Centers Announcement, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Proposal, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 30, Folders 3-4)
    - NIMH Summary Statement of HMHRC Proposal, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - NIMH, RFP Announcement, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - RFP Letter of Intent, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - RFP Consultants, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - RFP Progress, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - RFP meeting notes, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - RFP Budget material, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Scholar in Hispanic Alcohol Studies, 1983-1990
    - Grant Proposal, 1983 (Box 29, Folders 8-9)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Summary Statement, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Renewal Grant Proposal, 1987-1990 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Amado M. Padilla and Karen Lindholm, Socialization Processes Among Mexican Americans, 1976-1979
    - Original Proposal, 1976 (Box 36, Folders 8-9)
    - OCD Supplemental Funds, 1976-1978 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Transcription and Coding Manual, 1977-1978 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Socialization Processes Among Mexican Americans: A Sociolinguistic Analysis, First Year Report, 1977 (Box 37, Folders 2-4)
    - Socialization Processes Among Mexican Americans: A Sociolinguistic Analysis, Second Year Progress Report, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Socialization Practices Among Mexican Americans: A Sociolinguistic Analysis, Final Report, 1979 (Box 38, Folders 2-3)
    - Supplementary Request, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Amado M. Padilla, Clinical Research Proposal, 1980-1981
    - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Letters of Support, 1980-1981 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Revised Version, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Original Version, 1981 (Box 34, Folders 8-9)
    - Summary Statement (Disapproval), 1981 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - TACMR Conference (5/1-3/79 and 9/20-22/79, La Jolla, CA), 1979
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, internal, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, other, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Proposals, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Announcements, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Applications, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Participant Applications, 1979 (Box 23, Folders 8-12, Box 24, Folders 1-3)
    - Participants (selected), 1979 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Agenda, 5/1-3/79 Conference, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Agenda, 9/20-22/79 Conference, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Participant Questionaires, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Expenses, 9/20-22/79 Conference, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - National Conference of Hispanic Psychologists (11/29-12/2/79), 1979
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, internal, 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Proposal, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Particpants, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Agenda, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Conference Report, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Proposal for National Hispanic Psychological Association (NHPA), 1979 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Expenses, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Second Symposium on Chicano Psychology (3/26-3/27/82, UC-Riverside), 1982
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Participants, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Participants papers, 1982 (Box 25, Folders 3-4)
    - Announcements and Publicity, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Agenda, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Evaluations, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Expenses, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Ethnicity, Acculturation, and Mental Health Among Hispanics Conference (11/11-12/83, Albuquerque, NM), 1983
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, other, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Proposal, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Participants, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Announcements and publicity, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Agenda, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Evaluations, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Expenses, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - First Binational Conference on U.S.-Mexico Migration: Psychosocial Issues (11/12-14/87, Guadalajara, Mexico), 1987-11
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1985-1987 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986-1987 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Proposals, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Participants, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Abstracts, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Planning notes, 1987 (Box 28, Folders 1-2)
    - Announcements and publicity, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Agendas, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Introductory remarks, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Papers, 1987 (Box 28, Folders 6-8)
    - Expenses, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Conference report, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper articles, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Other conferences, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Hanes Conference, 1986
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, internal, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Hispanic Hanes Data Tape Technical Workshop (2/6-7/86), 1986-02 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Hispanic Hanes Summer Workshop Proposal, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Inquiries, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Participant applications, 1986 (Box 26, Folders 7-9)
    - Agendas, paticipants, consultants, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Participant proposals, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Evaluations, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Other conferences
    - 1983-1984 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - 1986 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Chicano Studies Research Center Symposium (2/21/87, Los Angeles, CA), 1987-02-21 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Primer Congreso Binacional, Migracion Mexico-Estados Unidos: Temas Psicolsociales [First Binational Conference, Mexico-U.S. Migration, Psychosocial issues], 1987-03-30 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Health and Behavior: Research Agenda for Hispanics (5/14-17/87, University of Illinois at Chicago), 1987-05 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Los Chicanos: Origen, presencia, y destino, Foro Universitario, Universidad de Colima (12/16-20/85, Colima, Mexico), 1985-1987 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Conference was held again on 7/1-7/5 1987 at the same location.
    - U.S.-Mexico Conference on Alcohol Related Issues (7/23-24/87, Los Angeles, CA), 1987-07 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Congreso-Binacional Mexico-E.U. Sobre temas de Alcholismo [Binational Mexico-U.S. Conference on Issues of Alcoholism] (7/23-25/87), 1987-07 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - First Regional North American Conference of the International Association for Cross-Cultural Psychology (8/16-21/87, Kingston, Canada), 1987-08 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - American Psychological Association, Annual Meeting (8/28-31/87, New York, NY), 1987-08 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Research Conference on Violence and Homicide in Hispanic Communities (9/14-15/87, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA), 1987-09 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Series 3. National Center for Bilingual Education and Research (NCBR)
  The National Center for Bilingual Research was created in November 1979 by the National Institute of Education under a cooperative agreement with the Southwest Regional Laboratory for Educational Research and Development (SWRL) in response to Congressional mandates under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act (ESEA). The NCBR, which was funded for a five year period, represented a major federal commitment to systematic research on bilingualism and bilingual education in the United States. The Center, which was directed by Padilla, carried out research and related activities in the areas of language acquisition, language functioning, and bilingual education. The Center officially closed in April 1985.
  - Work plans, proposals, reports, etc.
    - Plan of Work for FY 1981, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Plan of Work 1981 External Review Comments/Information, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Responses to Comments, 1979-10 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Draft Plan of Work for 1981, 1980-09 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Plan of Work for FY 1981, 1980-10 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Plan of Work for FY 1981, 1980-11 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Revised Cost Proposal, 1980-04 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Summaries, 1981-04 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Workplan on Social Policy Papers, Series in Bilingual Education, 1981-06 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Workplan for the Language Minority Youth Studies, 1981-06 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Third Quarter Performance Report, 1981-08 (Box 59, Folders 1-2)
    - Retrospective Report of Activities for FY Ending September 30, 1980, 1980-10-10 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Summary of Activities 11/15/1979 – 9/12/1980, 1979-1980 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Plan of Work/ Cost Proposal for FY 1982, 1981-06 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Proposed Modifications to 1982 Plan of Work, 1981-09 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Modified 1982 Plan of Work, 1981-11 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Proposed Supplemental Activity for FY 1982, 1981-11 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Supplementary Plan of Work & Cost Proposal FY 1982, 1982-03 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Plan of Work & Cost Proposal for FY 1983, 1982-08 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Plan of Work for FY 1984, Business Proposal (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Plan of Work for FY 1984, Technical Proposal (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Plan of Work 11/1984-4/1985 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Longitudinal Language Project
    - Volume 1: Similarities & Differences in Naturalistic English Speech of Native Spanish and Korean Speaking School Children. Arturo Romero, 1984-04 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Volume 2: Procedures Manual and Guide to the NCBR Longitudinal Study of Language Development in Bilingual Contexts. Draft. Garcia, Berdan, Kim, Padilla, 1982-12 (Box 61, Folder 2)